<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-09-19T16:07:40-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">teeny catalogue</title><subtitle>Joyce Rice is an experience designer with a focus in journalism and education. She make comics, games, and other digital products to help newsrooms and educators tell more vibrant stories.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Hello World!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/09/18/hello-world.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World!" /><published>2018-09-18T15:15:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-18T15:15:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/09/18/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/09/18/hello-world.html">&lt;p&gt;After undergrad, in 2010, I was desperate to go into information science. I researched programs in my area, priced them, out, came up with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Debt-to-income_ratio&quot;&gt;increasingly hair-brained schemes to pay for it&lt;/a&gt;. Part of this desperation came from graduating into a recession with a comics degree (ooops), but part of it was from feeling like I’d never keep anything straight now that I was out of school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a hunger for knowledge. My favorite website is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Main_Page&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; and my favorite place is the used book store. Despite this constrant quest for new information, I’ve never been great at recall; I don’t know &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/1398297-joycer?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;search%5Bquery%5D=stephen+king&quot;&gt;which Stephen King books I’ve read&lt;/a&gt;, I always doubt my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=chicken+of+the+woods&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwiigK2AjcjdAhW7HjQIHQcfC9YQ_AUIDigB&amp;amp;biw=1680&amp;amp;bih=948&quot;&gt;edible mushroom chops&lt;/a&gt;, and I can never remember the title of my &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books/about/HTML5.html?id=uuGbAgAAQBAJ&amp;amp;source=kp_book_description&quot;&gt;favorite book on HTML5&lt;/a&gt;. I have always needed clues. I have always relied heavily on information systems, and I’m always trying to optimize them, to better uplift my brain’s natural recall (or lack there of).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, my blog was a sketchbook, a place to store one kind of information. This was &lt;a href=&quot;http://teenyrobots.tumblr.com&quot;&gt;okay for a long time&lt;/a&gt;, but it never felt like a great place to write. As social media became more robust, it just started to seem like a poor amalgamation of several other disparate streams. It wasn’t the sort of catalog I was trying to create. Using lots of different places and tools on the internet, I tried to build the set of resources I was looking for, but it never quite emerged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several years away from blogging, I find myself looking for that robust catalog again. So many platforms have grown to replace the blogs of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/noughties&quot;&gt;the noughties&lt;/a&gt;, but I’m getting tired of the ways they control our speech—from format control, to limiting distribution, to outright censorship. None of them are great places to store ideas anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My need to file and save new information has only grown. Almost ten years later, I have a degree in game design as well as comics, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://teenyrobots.net/work.html&quot;&gt;I work with media companies on what it means to tell stories in digital spaces&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cca.edu/academics/faculty/jrice2&quot;&gt;I teach young artists the basic webstack&lt;/a&gt; so they can make their own art on the web (I also make them blog about it). I speak on creative collaboration and making basic design more accessible to other disciplines. I learn new things every day, and from so many sources, it sometimes seems like more dissipates than sticks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catalogs help us find things. We can store research, document new ideas, and create collections that inspire us. I’m looking forward to trying a new way to organize all the valuable bits I want to find again. I’m doing it in public because I think a lot of this work is worth sharing, so other folks don’t have to do the same legwork. Processes that can help other people that create art on the internet, resources we can all share, and things I’ve learned after 8+ years of working for myself. There are other places to store this kind of stuff, where one might accrue claps and favs and other sorts of internet points, but I’m tired of not owning and controlling my content, so I’m going to do it right here for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start, I’d like to share a few other catalogs that have inspired me to start researching, writing, and bookmarking in public again:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brainpickings.org/&quot;&gt;Brain Pickings&lt;/a&gt;, an inventory of cross-disciplinary interestingness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://austinkleon.com/&quot;&gt;Austin Kleon’s blog&lt;/a&gt;, a professional practices log (his newsletter is also pretty off the chain)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.annfriedman.com/weekly/&quot;&gt;Ann Friedman’s newsletter&lt;/a&gt;, a collection of news worth sharing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;tldr&lt;/em&gt;: dear mom, I decided to become a librarian after all&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="on" /><category term="bloggin" /><summary type="html">After undergrad, in 2010, I was desperate to go into information science. I researched programs in my area, priced them, out, came up with increasingly hair-brained schemes to pay for it. Part of this desperation came from graduating into a recession with a comics degree (ooops), but part of it was from feeling like I’d never keep anything straight now that I was out of school.</summary></entry></feed>